Aufa Billah Putra Jazama

Depok, Jawa Barat • aufaroot18@gmail.com • 6285216392129 • linkedin.com/in/aufabillah

Summary

Experienced more than 2 years in building solid and scalable Frontend applications. Currently working full-time as a Web Platform Engineer at Tokopedia. In addition, active as a part-time mentor at university and several training programs. Focus on building a career in the Software Engineering field.

Experience

Tokopedia

Kuningan, South Jakarta

Web Platform Engineer

July 2021 - Current

- Develop, maintain, scale features in Search tribe.
- Using Modern Technology (React, GraphQL, Emotion) to build a scalable web.
- Collaboration with various stakeholders to achieve innovation in Tokopedia.

Skilvul Depok, West Java

Mentor Full Stack (Part-Time)

Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

- Mentoring students of Kampus Merdeka Program Batch 5.
- Deliver Modern Full Stack Technology (MongoDB, Express, React, Node).
- Responsible for delivering best practice in software development mentoring.

STT Terpadu Nurul Fikri

Depok, West Java

Lecturer (Part-Time)

Sep 2021 - Current

- Teaching frontend and backend programming courses.
- Using React(Frontend) and Express (Backend) technology.
- Responsible for teaching 145 students (Frontend) and 101 students (Backend).

Education

STT TERPADU NURUL FIKRI

Depok, Jawa Barat

Bachelor Degree, Informatics, GPA 3.86

2 September 2019

Thesis: Building Event Website using Laravel App

Certifications

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT AND APIS

Freecodecamp

Feb 2022 - No Exp

freecodecamp.org/certification/aufaroot18/back-end-development-and-apis

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER EXPERT

Dicoding

July 2021 - July 2024

dicoding.com/certificates/1RXYYYWDQXVM

Skills

• Frontend: HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React

• Backend: PHP, Laravel, Node.js, Express

• Others: Linux, Figma